<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BEC</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main2">Bapatla College</string>

    <string name="awaaz_text"><b>AWAAZ</b> is an interacting hub of <b>Bapatla Engineering College students</b>, which\n Provides a platform to open up. Inculcates a fondness to <i>English language</i>. Hones up the elite <i>oratory skills</i>, <i>interpersonal skills</i>, <i>intrapersonal skills</i> and <i>communication skills</i> needed for personal interviews, group discussions etc. Helps the students groom their personalities and make them self-confident. Helps the members do away with the menace of Stage Fear.\n This is a platform for emphasizing the power of speech, enhancing critical thinking, and soft skills that are necessary to cope up with the real life situations. The club works with a mission to mould the students into well-rounded, well-informed individuals with sharp personalities and good communication skills. Knowledge is improved by sharing, so knowledge sharing is considered as the daily practice of every member of the club. Since its<b> Inception on 28th December, 2012</b> by a group of <b>senior students</b>, the club through its activities helped students in expressing each and every thought of theirs in words. This acts as a suitable platform to hone their <b>literary talents</b> with productive <i>suggestions, constructive criticism</i> and heartfelt appreciation. It accomplishes its objectives by conducting various events on weekly basis empowering the students in the <b>language skills, team work, presentations, spontaneity and leadership</b>. Some of those events are<i><b>\n &gt; Debates\n &gt; Elocution\n &gt; Essay Writing\n &gt; Fabulist\n &gt; Floor crossing\n &gt; Group Discussion\n &gt; Jam ( Just A Minute)\n &gt; Mock Interviews\n &gt; Mock Press\n &gt; Picture Perception\n &gt; Role Play\n &gt; Youth Parliament</b></i>\n Events related to Vocabulary like Word drop, Word wiz, Word Buzz etc\n Language Guidance Programme Creative Thinking and many more...\n Sessions here are designed to have fun along with ingrained learning process. The co-ordinators facilitate the event, come up with necessary tips and feedback that helps students overcome hesitation and stage fear. </string>
    <string name="cca_text">  <b>CCA</b> was established by <b>S.V.Amarnadh</b> of Mechanical Engineering Department &amp; , <b>K. Rupesh Kumar of Electronics</b>&amp; Communication Engineering Department in our college on 26th July, 2008 in the name of a cultural organization called<b><i> Centre For Creative Arts</i></b> .The main intention of starting CCA by them is to provide a platform that helps Students exhibit their creative and artistic talents, develop new skills, both artistic and managerial along with their academics, which in turn would help them achieve higher goals in their lives and this turned out to be the motto of CCA. The student members of CCA meet twice in a week and conduct sessions for a regular practice in their respective talents.\nThere are 4 main streams in CCA but not restricted to<b><i>\n> Arts\n> Dance\n> Dramatics\n> Singing\n</i></b>These streams are in turn categorized into many sub streams like for dance, there are sub streams like <i>western dance, hip hop, folk dance</i> etc., CCA extracts hidden talents of students in the above streams through learning sessions, video tutorials &amp; competitions.</string>
    <string name="sac_text"><b>SAC (SURYODAYA SOCIETY for AWAKENING COMMUNITY)</b> is a formal committee of students formed at <b>Bapatla Engineering College</b> with a motto \n<b>\'NO CHILD WORKING, EVERY CHILD IN SCHOOL &amp; LEARNING WELL\'</b>\n established by <i><b>N.Venu Gopala Rao on 3rd march 2008</b></i>.\nIt was officially registered as an <i><b>Social Welfare Organization on june 3rd 2011</b></i>(regd no:171 0f 2011 at narsaropet).\n<b>Objectives:-</b><i>\n> Educational Classes, providing libraries and conducting science exhibitions.\n> Residential Shelter Homes for children in vulnerable situations.\n> Rescue and survey operations for freeing working children.\n> Working closely with government on advocating the needs of vulnerable children (working children)\n> Creating Awareness among the citizens in villages about the importance of education.\n> Donating blood to the people in need.\n</i><b>Structure of SAC:-</b><i>\n> MONITORING TEAM\n> HOSTEL TEAM\n> VILLAGE TEAM\n> BLOOD TEAM\n> ACCOUNTING TEAM</i></string>


    <string name="notify">\t\t\t\t\tNOTIFICATIONS\n>>  College remains closed on 14&#8212;02&#8212;2018(Wednesday) due to the sad demise of founder president of BES Dr. Yarlagadda Krishnamurthy Garu.\n>>  Two Day Workshop on Recent Trends in Pavement Engineering (RTPE-2018) on February 16th &amp; 17th, 2018\n>Tomorrow is Badn due to a2+b2 behalf of Kasi Priayatham</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_notifications">Notifications &amp; Circulars</string>

    <string name="info">The Bapatla Engineering College(Autonomous), one of the seven educational institutions sponsored by the Bapatla Education Society, was established in 1981 with a vision to impart quality technical education and is affiliated to Acharya Nagarjuna University.\n View More About College--></string>


    <string name="bankdetails">Tuituion Fee\t31118744448\nSpecial, Condonation, Library, Id Card Fee\t31118765060\nHostel, Mess Fee\t31118762434\nBus Fee \t31113737009\nAutonomous Examination Fee\t31619409852\nTraining And Placemenet Fee\t31785855237\nUniversity Examination Fee\t31118759075\nUniversity Condonation Fee\t31118777609</string>


    <string name="collegeinfo">This College is one of the few Engineering Colleges in Andhra Pradesh, which is accredited by the National Board of Accreditation (NBA) of the All India Council for Technical Education (AICTE), New Delhi. The Five B. Tech. Courses which were accredited thrice are: Civil Engineering, Computer Science &amp; Engineering, Electonics and Communications Engineering, Electrical and Electonics Engineering &amp; Mechanical Engineering. The Electronics &amp; Instrumentation Engineering and Chemical Engineering courses were accredited twice and Infomation Technology was also accredited once.\nThe College became AUTONOMOUS in the academic Year 2010 - 11.</string>
    <string name="ci2">This College is one of the few Engineering Colleges in Andhra Pradesh, which is accredited by the <b>National Board of Accreditation (NBA)</b> of the <b>All India Council for Technical Education (AICTE), New Delhi</b>. The <b>Five</b> B. Tech. Courses which were accredited <b>thrice</b> are: <i>Civil Engineering, Computer Science &amp; Engineering, Electonics and Communications Engineering, Electrical and Electonics Engineering &amp; Mechanical Engineering. The Electronics &amp; Instrumentation Engineering and Chemical Engineering courses</i> were accredited <b>Twice</b> and Infomation Technology was also accredited once.
\n<b><i>The College became AUTONOMOUS in the academic Year 2010 - 11.</i></b>\n
<b>COURSES OFFERED</b>\n
<i><b>B.TECH</b></i>\n
The 4-year B. Tech. Courses is offered in eight branches\n
Civil Engineering(180), Chemical engineering(180), Computer Science &amp; Engineering(180), Electonics and Communications Engineering(180), Electrical and Electonics Engineering(180), Electronics &amp; Instrumentation Engineering(60), Information Technology(120) and Mechanical Engineering(180)\nLateral Entry is of 20%\n
<i><b>M.TECH</b></i>\n
<i>
Five M.Tech. Courses (1) ‘CAD/CAM’ specialization in Mech. Engg. Dept., (2) ‘COMMUNICATIONS &amp; SIGNAL PROCESSING’ in ECE Dept., (3) ‘COMPUTER SCIENCE &amp; ENGG.’ In CSE Dept., (4)\'POWER SYSTEM\' in EEE Dept., and (5)\'STRUCTURAL ENGINEERING\' in Civil Dept. are also offered.</i>
        \n\nThe college is selected as a Network Institute for the Technical Education Quality Improvement Programme (TEQIP) of the Ministry of Human Resources Development and the World Bank. An amount of Rs. 11.81 crores was granted to the college under this programme.The college has excellent infrastructural facilities of buildings with a total plinth area of Six Lakh sq. ft., equipment worth Rs.10 crores, individual Computer Centres for all departments with latest systems and software, 20 Mbps leased-line and 40 Mbps broadband Internet facility, spacious library with rich collection of library books and journals etc. The facilities on the campus include a Girls’ Hostel to accommodate 500 students, 11 buses owned by the college for transport of day scholars, a subsidized canteen, adequate facilities for games &amp; sports, mineral water plant (1500 Lts/hour), two stand-by generators (250 KVA &amp; 82.5 KVA) etc. The college has NCC and NSS units.The performance of the students in the University (Acharya Nagarjuna University) examinations and at National level competitive examinations like Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering (GATE) has been consistently good. Every year, ten students on an average get all India ranks below 100 in GATE. In GATE-1997, our student had secured All India First Rank in Civil Engineering branch. Our students have also bagged overall First Rank in University examinations on a number of occasions. Considerable numbers of students of our college are getting selected every year in campus placements. About 75-80% of the students get either placements or secure admission for higher studies (M.Tech. within the country at IITs and other reputed institutes or M.S. in foreign universities) every year.
</string>
    <string-array name="attand">
        <item>0</item>
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>5</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="branch">
        <item>Computer Science</item>
        <item>Chemical</item>
        <item>Civil</item>
        <item>Instrumentation</item>
        <item>Electrical</item>
        <item>Electronics and Communication</item>
        <item>Mechanical</item>
        <item>Information Technology</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="year">
        <item>2nd</item>
        <item>3rd</item>
        <item>4th</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="csedept">The Department of Computer Science and Engineering was started in 1994-95 and accrediated by NBA thrice in the years : 2003, 2007 &amp; 2012.\nDepartment is headed by<b><u> Dr.SK.Nazeer </u></b> .\nThe department strives hard to impart quality education and to keep the students on the competitive edge of the present-day technology.</string>
    <string name="ecedept">The Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering was established in the year 1981 .The National Board of Accreditation has accredited the department for three years.\nDepartment is headed by<b><u> Dr. B. Chandra Mohan </u></b>\nDepartment have 38 faculty and are members of professional bodies like ISTE,IEEE,IETE and CSI. All the students are the members of IETE student forum of the existing department. Having state of the art laboratories to gain good knowledge in the field of Electronics, Communication, Microwave, VLSI, DSP&amp;IMAGE, Networking Microprocessor and Microcontroller.</string>
    <string name="eeedept">This Department was established in 1995 and now offering Diploma (DEEE) with an intake of 60, B.Tech (EEE) with an intake of 180 and M.Tech (Power Systems engineering) with an intake of 18.\nDepartment is headed by<b><u> Dr.N.Rama Devi </u></b>\n. The department has Electrical Machines Lab, Computer Simulation Lab, Power Electronics Lab, Electrical Measurements Lab,Control Systems Lab,Micro processers Lab, Electical Workshop Lab and Power Systems Lab with state of art equipment.</string>
    <string name="eiedept">The Department of Electronics &amp; Instrumentation Engineering was established in the year 1994. The department offers 4 year B.Tech. degree program in Electronics &amp; Instrumentation Engineering with an annual intake of 60 Students.\nDepartment is headed by<b><u> Prof. CH.Ramesh </u></b>\n.The Department is accredited twice by NBA of AICTE. The Department is covered under<i> TEQIP </i></string>
    <string name="mechdept">The Department was established in 1981. As on today twenty eight batches passed out with excellent academic performance.\nDepartment is headed by\n<b><u> Dr. T.Nancharaiah</u></b>\n .The Department has excellent lab facilities with state of the art equipment and it has highly qualified, experienced and committed faculty members.</string>
    <string name="civdept">The Department of Civil Engineering was started from the very inception of Bapatla Engineering College in 1981 and so far has produced nearly 1850 graduates.\nDepartment is headed by\n<b><u> Dr. CH.N.Satish Kumar</u></b>\n.Over the years the department has shown remarkable progress in academics. The department was nurtured in the hands of<b> Dr S R Parimi.</b></string>
    <string name="chemdept">The Department of Chemical Engineering which is accredited by NBA (National Board of Accreditation) from March 2007 was established in the year 1997 and has been offering under graduate course with an intake of 60 students, has excellent laboratory, library facilities including a well established computer center.\nDepartment is headed by<b><u> Dr. J. S. Rao</u></b>\n It has lofty aims of producing integrated students of highest caliber with dedicated and diligent faculty members from reputed institutions like IITs, NITs and Universities.</string>
    <string name="itdept">The Department of Information Technology was started in the year 1999. The department offers B.Tech in Information Technology with an annual intake of 120. The department is equipped with the state of the art computing facilities and experienced faculty members. It is known for its academic excellence proved by its performances since its inception.\nDepartment is headed by<b><u> Sri N. Siva Ram Prasad</u></b>\n.The department has established one centre of excellence by name MIC (Microsoft Innovation Centre) in collaboration with Microsoft.</string>
    <string name="notification">%1$s is the notification</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-5316829605239412/4438025691</string>
</resources>
